Sadashiv Nandanikar

Machine Learning Engineer

■ nandanikar.sadashiv0712@gmail.com

+91-8431114989

Pune, Maharashtra

₽ PROFILE

To gain employment with a company or institution that offers me a consistently positive atmosphere to learn new technologies and implement them for the betterment of the business. Have expertise in python and related libraries, data analysis, mathematics statistics, designing machine learning algorithms, text preprocessing, finding solutions using NLP tools and designing REST API.

ន្លាំ SKILLS

Python — Pandas, NumPy, Scikit-learn, Seaborn, Matplotlib, Regular Expression, Data Visualization.

Database — MySQL, MongoDB

Operating Systems — Windows, Linux

Cloud Platform/Service — AWS

Text Processing — NLTK, TF-IDF, Word2Vec, Bag of Words, Stemming and Lemmatization

Machine Learning — Linear Regression, Ridge & Lasso Regression, Logistic Regression, Naive Bayes, K Nearest Neighbour's Classifier, Support Vector Machine, Decision Tree, Random Forest, Gradient Descent, AdaBoost, Gradient Boosting, XG Boosting, K-means clustering, DBSCAN, PCA.

Web Framework — Flask, Streamlit

LANGUAGES

English | Marathi | Hindi

EDUCATION

B.E (Bachelor of Engineering),

Visvesvaraya Technological University, Belgaum 2013 – 2017

& INTERESTS

Reading Books: Atomic Habits, Who Moved My

Cheese? | Anime: One Piece, Naruto

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Machine Learning Engineer, Codify Software Services 09/2022 – present | Pune

APS fault Detection

- Implemented preventive maintenance for APS-related machine breakdowns
- Analyzed operational challenges and extracted insights from diverse data sources
- Developed scalable data pipelines for rapid learning and predictive modeling
- Collaborated with data and production engineering teams to design ML infrastructure,
- conducting data cleansing, transformation, feature engineering, analysis, and visualization.

Sentiment Analysis on Customer Reviews of Services Station

- Developed a hybrid NLP & ML model for sentiment analysis to gauge customer reactions towards company products.
- Conducted text processing, cleaning, and advanced preprocessing to prepare raw data for analysis.
- Created data pipelines and architecture for efficient data processing.
- Implemented key phrase extraction techniques such as YAKE and RAKE for insightful analysis.
- Collaborated in daily stand-up calls, actively contributing to task assignments and data analysis efforts.

SBM-Master Data Mangement, Flex

02/2022 - 09/2022 | Pune

- Analyzed supplier transactional data to identify trends and optimize procurement strategies.
- Collaborated with suppliers and internal teams to resolve pricing and commercial terms, leveraging data-driven insights.
- Prepared and delivered reports, analysis, and actionable recommendations to support informed decision-making.
- Managed vendor data and updates, ensuring data integrity and facilitating efficient vendor onboarding processes.

Design Engineer, Success Automation

01/2019 - 02/2022 | Pune

- Designed and implemented special purpose machines for diverse manufacturing clients.
- Created data-driven solutions, such as the Production Efficiency Dashboard, to provide actionable insights and support informed decision-making in production management.
- Collaborated cross-functionally to ensure designs and data solutions met client objectives and industry standards.
- Optimized production processes, reducing time and enhancing worker productivity, resulting in positive client feedback and increased competitiveness.

PROJECTS

CropGuard 🗹

Brand Recognition 🖸

Rental Bike Price Prediction

Vegetable Recognition 🖸